A Guide to the Kiwanis Club of Arlington Records, 1931-2006
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Kiwanis Club of Arlington Records, 1931-2006
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 102
7 boxes.
Kiwanis Club of Arlington
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Kiwanis Club of Arlington in 2002 and 2008.
Historical Information
Founded in 1915, the Kiwanis Club is an international community service organization. The Arlington chapter was founded in June 1931. On Charter night, August 12, 1931, there were 25 members. Originally for men only, the Arlington Kiwanis started accepting women members in 1988, after the international organization voted to change the membership rules. Until World War II, activities centered on youth work, such as picnics for underprivileged children and the Boy and Girl Scouts. During the war, there was more emphasis on patriotic and civil defense activities. After the war, emphasis returned to raising money to give to local charitable groups and to youth development organizations. The following is a sampling of recipients of the club's donations: local chapters of the Red Cross and Salvation Army, the Arlington Hospital and Arlington YMCA, Hospice of Northern Virginia, and Meals-on-Wheels.
Scope and Content
RG 102 houses the records of the Kiwanis Club of Arlington, Virginia. The record group measures three linear feet and dates from 1931 to 2006. Types of material include minutes, newsletters, correspondence, club histories, reports, posters and other publicity materials, clippings, and financial records.
Series 1 contains Board minutes, 1931-1957 and 1980-1981, and document the club's plans for raising and distributing funds. Fundraising activities included peanut sales and especially in later years, an annual oyster/pig roast and a series of narrated travelogue films. Series 2, Travelogue Files, documents this major activity from 1979-1996 and includes film lists, contracts, budgets, correspondence, and publicity materials. Attendance at the travelogues was somewhat lower in the 1990s.
The club has maintained enthusiasm with weekly luncheon meetings and the weekly newsletter, Arki (for Ar lington Ki wanis). Series 3, Newsletters, covers 1936-2005 (bulk 1976-2005) and contains the newsletters. This series constitutes approximately half the collection. Arki summarizes club luncheons and other activities and often has included photographs and cartoons and encourages members to maintain a high level of involvement in charitable fund-raising. There are several volume numbering irregularities (e.g. there are two volumes 29 and 30 and no volumes 35-48). Series 4, Miscellaneous, has various club items that are not part of the above series. It includes histories of the Arlington Kiwanis, membership brochures, and a photograph of membership as of February 13, 2006.
Arrangement
Record Group 102 is organized into four series by type of material. Arrangement within series is generally chronological. Oversized materials, including one photograph, have been removed and placed in proper storage in Box 7. Folders with oversized materials have an asterisk [*] to denote where material was removed and separation sheets added.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Researchers interested in the Kiwanis Club RG 98, Records of the Ki-Wives of Arlington, and RG 197, South Arlington Kiwanis Club Records. There are many other record groups for local Arlington civic organizations throughout the Arlington Community Archives.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Kiwanis International; Clubs.; Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Board Minutes
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Treasurer's Reports, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Monthly Reports, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Budget, Treasurer's Reports, Annual Report, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Budget, Treasurer's Reports, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Budget, Treasurer's Reports, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Budget, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Budget, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Yearbook, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Budget, Yearbook, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Budget, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Monthly Reports, Annual Report, Yearbook, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, 1956 and Report of the President of Ki-Wives, 1955-56 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Annual Report, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes: 50th Anniversary Year, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
- Travelogue Files
  - Travelogue Address Files (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Contract and Costs, 1979-1993 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue: HIstory of Programs and Ticket Sales/Costs, 1980-1993 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Programs and Season Ticket Forms, 1982-1991 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Income/Expense Reports, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Programs from McLean, Va. and Other Places, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Season Ticket Lists, Budget, REceipts, Advertisements, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Budget, Season Ticket List, Receipts, Advertisements, Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Budget, Advertisements, Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Correspondence, Advertisements, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Receipts, Client Lists, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Publicity Photographs, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Season Tickets, Receipts, Advertisements, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Correspondence, 1995-1996, Richmond, Virginia Kiwanis Report, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Travelogue Budget, Advertisements, Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - Windoes Travelogue Information, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Windoes Travelogue Advertising Recordings, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Travelogue Receipts, Correspondence, Advertisements, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Travelogue Receipts, Budget, Advertisements, Correspondence, 1998-99 (Box 3)
  - Travelogue Correspondence, Receipts, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Travelogue Posters, 1996-1999 * (Box 3)
- Newsletters
  - Arki Newsletter, February 24, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 23, no. 3-9, (February 3, 1954-April 28, 1954) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletter, vol. 24, no. 6, (March 23, 1955) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletter, vol. 27, no. 24, (July 9, 1958) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletter, vol. 28, no. 40, (December 9, 1959) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 29, no. 7-33, (February 17, 1960-August 24, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 30, no. 1-46 (January 4, 1961-November 29, 1961) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, [2nd] vol. 29, no. 16-49, (January 14, 1976-September 1, 1977) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, [2nd] vol. 30, no. 1-52, (October 7, 1976-October 6, 1977) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 31, no. 2-52, (October 13, 1977-September 27, 1978) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 32, no. 1-52, (October 4, 1978-September 28, 1979) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 33, no. 1-39, (October 3, 1979-June 25, 1980) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 34, no. 1-42, (October 1, 1980-July 22, 1981) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 49, no. 42-52, (July 29, 1981-October 14, 1981) (Box 3)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 50, no. 3-52, (October 21, 1981-September 29, 1982) (Box 4)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 51, no. 1-20, (October 6, 1982-February 16, 1983) (Box 4)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 52, no. 21-52, (February 23, 1983-September 28, 1983) (Box 4)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 53, no. 1-51, (October 5, 1983-September 26, 1984) (Box 4)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 54, no. 1-51, (October 3, 1984-September 18, 1985) (Box 4)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 55, no. 1-52, (October 2, 1985-September 24, 1986) (Box 4)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 56, no. 1-52, (October 1, 1986-September 30, 1987) (Box 4)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 57, no. 1-52, (October 7, 1987-September 28, 1988) (Box 5)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 58, no. 1-52, (October 5, 1988-September 27, 1989) (Box 5)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 59, no. 1-51, (October 4, 1989-September 2, 1990) (Box 5)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 60, no. 1-52, (October 3, 1990-September 25, 1991) (Box 5)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 61, no. 1-53, (October 2, 1991-September 30, 1992) (Box 5)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 62, no. 1-52, (October 7, 1992-September 27, 1993) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 63, no. 1-52, (October 6, 1993-September 28, 1994) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 64, no. 1-52, (October 5, 1994-September 27, 1995) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 65, no. 1-52, (October 4, 1995-September 25, 1996) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 66, no. 1-52, (October 2, 1996-September 24, 1997) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 67, no. 1-52A, (October 1, 1997-September 30, 1998) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 68, no. 1-53, (October 7, 1998-September 29, 1999) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 69, no. 1-51, (October 6, 1999-September 27, 2000) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 70, no. 1-51, (October 4, 2000-September 26, 2001) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 71, no. 1-52, (October 3, 2001-September 25, 2002) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 72, no. 1-50, (October 2, 2002-September 24, 2003) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 73, no. 1-50, (October 1, 2003-September 29, 2004) (Box 6)
  - Arki Newsletters, vol. 74, no. 1-55, (October 6, 2004-September 28, 2005) (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous
  - Member Directories, 1980s (Box 6)
  - History of the Arlington Kiwanis Club, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Badge of Dave Carlson, Director, 1990s (Box 6)
  - History of the Arlington Kiwanis Club, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Membership Brochures and Other Club Materials, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Kiwanis Insurance Information, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Photograph of Membership, February 13, 2006* (Box 6)
- BOX 7 (OV)
  - Travelogue Posters, 1996-1999 (from Series 2, File 22) (Box 6)
  - Photograph of Membership, February 13, 2006 (from Series 4, File 7) (Box 6)